Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/louisehwerhemuepha-3665854b (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

C++

Matlab

Mathematica

Honors-Awards

Chapman University Student Employee of the Year (2011-2012)

Allergan Scholarship

President's Recognition Award

Publications

A collective approach to reducing carbon-dioxide emission: a case study of four university of Lagos halls of residence

A more powerful unconditional exact test of homogeneity for 2 × c contingency table analysis

Clinical and psychosocial factors associated with patient experience in pediatrics

Speeding up codon analysis on the cloud with local mapreduce aggregation

The Effect of Malnutrition on the Risk of Unplanned 7-Day Readmission in Pediatrics

Louis Ehwerhemuepha

Data Scientist at CHOC Children's and Affiliated Scholar, Chapman University

Orange, California

Summary

My primary interest is in healthcare data science or related opportunities that also allow for research and peer reviewed publications.

My experience encompasses theoretical, empirical, and applied statistical/biostatistical analyses and the application of machine learning and artificial intelligence algorithms on unstructured clinical data.

Experience

CHOC Children's

Data Scientist

June 2015 - Present (4 years 10 months)

Orange, California

I lead the Data Science initiatives at CHOC through applied and empirical research in Statistics, Machine Learning, and Artificial Intelligence. We have deployed several models in use by clinicians towards improving the quality of care of our patients.

Chapman University
Affiliated Scholar
February 2018 - Present (2 years 2 months)
Orange, California

CHOC

Volunteer Intern (Clinical data analysis) August 2014 - May 2015 (10 months)

Orange County, California Area

Statistical data analysis (cross sectional and longitudinal) in R

Chapman University 3 years 8 months Adjunct Faculty January 2013 - May 2015 (2 years 5 months)

Teaching introduction to computer science (programming) and statistics

Adjunct Faculty, Dept. of Physics, Computational Sciences & Engineering

August 2012 - December 2012 (5 months)

Taught a weekly Physics Lab class session.

Graduate Research Assistant

July 2012 - August 2012 (2 months)

Assisted faculty in data simulation and management of software development and statistical analysis in R. Family based association tests using FBAT.

Physics Tutor/Supplemental Instructor October 2011 - July 2012 (10 months)

Tutoring students offering first year Physics at Chapman University

Experian

Marketing Research Intern July 2013 - August 2013 (2 months)

- Obtained work experience with Adobe Marketing Cloud tools such as SiteCatalyst for web analytics
- Performed exploratory data analysis on Experian's tenure data to provide insight into customer retention
- Developed a simple forecast model with my supervisor to predict monthly revenue for the marketing team

NCEEC - Energy Commision of Nigeria Graduate Assistant December 2009 - August 2011 (1 year 9 months) University of Lagos, Nigeria

Research in energy efficiency and conservation opportunities in Nigeria.

Participation in energy efficiency and conservation programs/surveys and in

the process of energy efficiency policy formulation in Nigeria. Maintenance of

Centre's website and programming tasks when necessary.

International Center for Basic Research, Nigeria Python Demonstrator July 2011 - July 2011 (1 month)

Nigeria

Demonstrating the use of Python for Scientific Programming as an Introduction to Computational Science at the International Seminar on Theoretical Physics and National Development (ISOTPAND 2010). Consequently taught Python and its application to programming numerical method and simulation of simple physical phenomenon during some sessions of the program.

Data Easy Systems

Trainee Engineer

September 2009 - November 2009 (3 months)

Installation, maintenance and troubleshooting of VSATs and structured cabling systems. Basic Operating Systems Installation.

Project E Delta, Nigeria Undergraduate Internship December 2006 - March 2007 (4 months)

Delta State Secretariat, Nigeria

Computer Software and Hardware maintenance, troubleshooting of computer network connection problems and installation of Operating Systems.

Education

Chapman University

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.), Computational Science · (2011 - 2015)

Chapman University

M.S., Computational Sciences · (2011 - 2013)

Delta State University (NG)

B.Sc, Physics · (2004 - 2007)